DOMINIQUE STRAUSS

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Cape Town, South Africa. **Address**

Contact Number +27 (0)79 188 9414

Email Address DStraussPro@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/dominique-strauss LinkedIn https://github.com/DomStrauss Github

Gender Female 27.08.1996 Date of Birth Nationality South African

English, Afrikaans (Fluent Speak, Read and Write) Languages

Valid Driver's License Driver's Licence

Hello! I'm Dominique, I obtained my highest degree, Master of Science (MSc) in Genetics, from the University of the Free State in 2022. I am currently interested in furthering my studies in programming and data science. My work experience includes 1.5+ years as an Associate Validation Team Lead at IQVIA. My research experience includes 4 published articles in peer reviewed scientific journals from my master's research project, all of in which I am the leading author. I am currently furthering my programming experience in the programming languages HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, and Python.

QUALIFICATIONS

Masters of Science (MSc) in Genetics **BSc Honours Behavioural Genetics** BSc Genetics and Biochemistry

Grade 12

Advanced skills:

Microsoft Office

Scientific Grade Research Molecular Laboratory Skills University of the Free State, 2019 to 2021

University of the Free State, 2018

University of the Free State, 2015 to 2017

Pretoria Girls High, 2012 to 2014

SKILLS

Basic Skills:

HTML5, CSS, JavaScript

SQL, Database Validation, Data Entry, Data analysis

Project Management

EXPERIENCE

COMPANY IQVIA

DATE January 2022 to Present

Associate Validation Team Lead (Database analyst) TITLE **DUTIES**

- Advanced understanding of database structures
 - Perform validation of clinical research forms prior to site go live
 - Understand all the documentation requirements with regards to validation very well and update all relevant documents in a timely manner. Monitor documentation compliance for junior team members.
 - Expected to take complete responsibility for delivery of a validation project.
 - Ensure validation processes and best practices are being followed strictly by self and team.
 - Assist with creation and review of best practices and internal team processes
 - Identify areas for process improvement continuously.
 - Conduct Quality Review on projects on an ongoing basis as applicable.
 - Serve as Subject Matter Expert (SME) where applicable.
 - Mentor new joiner colleagues when assigned.

2. INSTITUTION : University of the Free State

DATE : January 2017 to December 2022

TITLE : Research Assistant and Demonstrator

DUTIES : - Teach quality standards (i.e., Good Laboratory Practice (GLP) and Good

Clinical Practice (GCP)) to students.

- Demonstrate laboratory techniques to students (i.e., Pipetting, Gel

Electrophoresis, Polymerase Chain Reaction (PCR)) to students.

3. INSTITUTION : University of the Free State

DATE : January 2019 to December 2022

TITLE : MSc student support

DUTIES : - Coordinate meetings and training activities relevant for projects and

Source the relevant, accredited training providers, determine the costs

and dates (Publications and Conferences).

- Drafting of all relevant funding documentation.

- Drafting of SOPs according to the International Conference on Harmonization (ICH), Good Clinical Practice (GCP), relevant local laws,

regulations, and guidelines towards clinical trial conduct.

- Drafting and submission of all application documentation for Ethics

Committees and Departmental Boards.

- Provide support with publication submissions, alterations and re-

submissions.

- Ensure budget spending is within the required limits.

- Research money saving methods and alternatives

- Monitor progress of 1st year master students.

- Assist senior master students where applicable.

Coordinate initiatives to foster collaborations between peers and

different university departments (Multi-Departmental Forum).

PUBLICATIONS -

- 1. Strauss, D., Ghosh, S., Murray, Z., & Gryzenhout, M. (2023). Global species diversity and distribution of the psychedelic fungal genus Panaeolus. *Heliyon*. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e16338
- 2. Strauss, D., Ghosh, S., Murray, Z., & Gryzenhout, M. (2022). Psilocybin containing mushrooms: a rapidly developing biotechnology industry in the psychiatry, biomedical and nutraceutical fields. 3 Biotech, 12(12), 339. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13205-022-03355-4
- 3. Strauss, D., Ghosh, S., Murray, Z., & Gryzenhout, M. (2022). An overview on the taxonomy, phylogenetics and ecology of the psychedelic genera Psilocybe, Panaeolus, Pluteus and Gymnopilus. Frontiers in Forests and Global Change, 5, 813998. https://doi.org/10.3389/ffgc.2022.813998
- 4. Strauss, D., Ghosh, S., Murray, Z., & Gryzenhout, M. (2021). Genomic DNA extraction from minimal amount of dried mushroom samples. Microbial Biosystems, 6(1), 49-54. https://doi.org/10.21608/MB.2021.91637.1036

· COURSES -

- 1. Project Management Simplified (2021)
- 2. Introduction to Bioinformatics, H3ABioNet (2019)

D E			- 6	-	
RE	FE	ΚI	ΞIN	ıL	ES

1. Ryno Esterhuizen, Line Manager at IQVIA

Contact:

· ryno.esterhuizen@iqvia.com · +27(0)83 798 8520· linkedin.com/in/ryno-esterhuizen-430694150/·

2. Soumya Ghosh, Ph. D.Co-supervisor for MSc Degree.

"I unconditionally recommend Ms Strauss." - Dr Ghosh

Contact:

· GhoshS@ufs.ac.za · +27(0)81 536 7344 · linkedin.com/in/soumya-ghosh-ph-d-05201515 ·

3. Marieka Gryzenhout, Ph. D. Main Supervisor for MSc Degree.

"I have seldom met someone such as Ms Strauss who has exhibited a high level of independence, responsibility focus, versatility and adventure." – Dr Gryzenhout

Contact:

· GryzenhoutM@ufs.ac.za · +27(0)81 320 2933 · linkedin.com/in/marieka-gryzenhout-89a2b446 ·

4. Zurika Murray, M. Sc. Program Director and co-supervisor for MSc Degree.

Contact:

· MurrayZ@ufs.ac.za · +27(0)82 336 4382 · linkedin.com/in/zurikamurray ·